(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-08-24T16:47:54.579506",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
みんなと見届ける！4周年カウントダウン
Countdown to the 4th Anniversary: Witnessing it with everyone!
うー、あー、もー、はい
Ooh, ah, mo, hai...
やだやだ ミスってらんない、ね？
No way, no way, I can't mess up, right?
真っ赤なハート差し出して…
Extending a bright red heart...
そんなのやっぱ妄想じゃん
That's just wishful thinking after all.
そっちはどう思ってるの 言いかけて仕舞う
What do you think? I almost say it, then hold back.
無理みたい こんなんじゃ…って
Thinking, 'It's no use like this...'
わかってるんだ 思うほどに
I know it, the more I think about it,
ハマっていくんだ 頑張りたい
the deeper I fall. I want to do my best,
あてしに期待 ぎゅーってしたいかも…
expecting of myself, maybe wanting a tight hug...
かもうん
maybe, yeah.
ちょっとは変われて いますか？
Have I changed even a little bit?
足りない とこ ばっかりだけど
Even though I'm full of shortcomings,
ポン で コツ で ドジ じゃ ない あてし
I'm not just clumsy, foolish, and awkward.
だったら きみ は だめだ よ ね？
If so, you wouldn't like that, right?
ねぇ もう やだやだ ミスってらんない
Hey, no more, no way, I can't mess up.
もう やだやだ 踊ってベイビダンス
No more, no way, dance to the Baby Dance!
あてしはまだ諦めない
I still won't give up.
でもでも全然だめかも
But maybe it's totally no good.
だってベイビダンス うまくできないの
Because I can't do the Baby Dance well.
だってベイビダンス 伝えられないの
Because I can't convey it with the Baby Dance.
もっと可愛くなりたいのに どうしたらいいかとか わかんないし
Even though I want to be cuter, I don't know what to do.
やだやだ ミスってらんない、ね？
No way, no way, I can't mess up, right?
あーやっちまった こんなはずじゃ
Ah, I messed up, this wasn't supposed to happen.
どうしてどうして わかっているのに
Why, why, even though I understand?
見せたくない とこ 透けちゃってさ
The parts I don't want to show are peeking through.
無理無理 でも期待は したいな いいですか？
No way, but I still want to hope. Is that okay?
ポン も コツ も ドジ も 全部あてしなんだよ ちゃんと見ていてほしい
Clumsiness and all are part of me. I want you to watch properly.
ねぇ もう やだやだ ぐずって後悔
Hey, no more, whining and regretting.
もう やだやだ 回ってベイビダンス
No more, spinning around in the Baby Dance!
だめなあてし塗り替えたい
I want to repaint my useless self.
でもでも全然だめかも
But maybe it's totally no good.
だってベイビダンス うまくできないの
Because I can't do the Baby Dance well.
だってベイビダンス
Because the Baby Dance...
はじまりの瞬間さ
The moment it all begins,
追い風は砂塵あげた
the tailwind kicked up dust.
立ち止まってられない
I can't just stand still.
上手にやり過ごしても
Even if I skillfully get by,
本当に欲しいもの 抱きしめなきゃ
I gotta hold onto what I truly desire;
いつも満たされない
I'm always left unsatisfied.
探しに行こう 果てしない大空へ
Let's go search the endless sky!
刻む 足跡 鮮やかに
Carving footprints so brightly,
きっと君と描き出そう
I'll surely paint it out with you.
走り出せ 誰も知らない未来
Start running toward an unknown future,
飛び込んだ その時に
and at the moment I jumped in,
輝いた 君の瞳 感じた
I felt the sparkle in your eyes.
素晴らしい 明日がもう 待っているから
A wonderful tomorrow is already waiting for us.
どんなに誤魔化しても
No matter how much I deceive myself,
これこそが現実さ でもね
this is reality, but you know...
もう目は逸らさない
I won't look away anymore.
誰かの幸せとか 横取りしたくなっちゃうけどね
Sometimes I want to snatch someone else's happiness,
それじゃ満たされない
but that won't satisfy me.
想像よりも 胸焦がす 真実を
The truth that burns in my chest more than imagination—
見つめる勇気 握りしめ もっと 君と始めよう
grab hold of the courage to face it, and let's start with you!
朝焼けが いつか夢見た未来
The morning glow illuminating the future we dreamed of
照らしてくれているから
is shining upon us,
手を繋ぎ 今すぐに 飛び出そう
so let's hold hands and jump out right now!
素晴らしい 明日は ほら 僕らの ためにあるから
A wonderful tomorrow is right there for us.
迷っても 失っても あの空の向こうで
Even if we hesitate or lose, beyond that sky,
終わらない 物語 は 今日もまた 色を変えて 瞬くよ
the never-ending story changes colors and twinkles today.
さあ 扉 開けて
Come on, open the door!
走り出せ 誰も知らない未来
Start running toward an unknown future,
飛び込んだ その時に
and at the moment I jumped in,
輝いた 君の瞳 感じた
I felt the sparkle in your eyes.
素晴らしい 明日が もう 僕らを待っているから
Because a wonderful tomorrow is already waiting for us.
ゆらゆらり、風に乗って
Gently swaying on the wind,
ハート型の花びら
heart-shaped petals
はらりひらり、舞い降りる
flutter down and land
あなたの元届いて
right to where you are.
ポケットの中に隠した
Tucked inside my pocket,
私との思い出と
the memories we shared
言葉にならない想いが
and unspoken feelings
あなたに伝わりますように
I hope they reach you.
大きな風に負けないように
So we won't lose to the great wind,
交わした約束忘れない
we'll never forget the promise we made.
小さな声で呼びかけるから
Calling out in a small voice,
小指を繋いで微笑んで
linking pinkies and smiling.
春の香りは あなたの香り
The scent of spring is your scent,
そっと胸くすぐるの
gently tickling my chest.
そっとそっと、ほのか香る
Softly, softly, faintly fragrant,
優しく胸染み込む
gently sinking into my heart.
つゆくつゆく、願っている
Constantly, earnestly wishing
輝いている明日を
for a shining tomorrow.
二人の道いま始まる
Our path together begins now.
途中で迷ったなら 見上げれば
If you ever lose your way, just look up
手を差し伸べる あなたいるから
and reach out your hand—because you're there,
踏み出せる
we can take that step forward.
大きな風を受け止めていく
Embracing the strong winds as we go.
笑顔も涙も無くさない
With neither smiles nor tears lost,
小さなため息 聞こえた時には
whenever I hear a little sigh,
ぎゅっと抱きしめてあげるから
I'll hold you tight.
繰り返してく季節感じて
Feeling the repeating seasons,
歩いてく これからも
we'll keep walking from now on.
ゆらゆらり、でも失わない
Gently swaying, but never losing it,
いつか夢見た未来
the future I once dreamed of.
照らしてくれるから
Because you'll light it up for me,
手を繋ぎ
let's hold hands
今すぐに飛び出そう
and run out right now!
素晴らしい明日へほら
Toward a wonderful tomorrow, look!
僕らのためにあるから
It's waiting right there for us.
誰も知らない未来
A future nobody knows yet—
飛び込んだその時に
at the very moment we jumped in,
輝いた 君の瞳から
from your shining, tear-filled eyes,
素晴らしい 明日へほら
Toward a wonderful tomorrow, look!
僕らを待っているから
It's waiting right there for us.
君の瞳から零れた
Welling up in your eyes,
素晴らしい 明日へほら
Toward a wonderful tomorrow, look!
僕らを待っているから
It's waiting right there for us.
わんつーで参戦！
One, two, enlist!
みこみこみこ！
Miko miko miko!
ついに来たよお待たせ！
You're finally here, thanks for waiting!
待ちに待った？ うへへへ
Have you been waiting? Ehehehe.
電脳世界からやってきた
I came straight from cyberspace!
ウザカワ系バーチャル巫女アイドル
The annoying-cute virtual shrine maiden idol!
わたしはそうエリート！
I am so elite!
なんて言ったってエリート！
Whatever you say, elite!
エリート巫女？ エリートアイドル？
Elite shrine maiden? Elite idol?
そんなの両方に決まってるじゃん！
It's definitely both!
いじわるも泣き虫もカミサマも？
Tease me, crybaby, even the gods?
崇め奉れ巫女パワーで
Worship me with shrine maiden power
幸せ分けてあげるんだよ？
so I can share some happiness with you!
みこみこみこで ほにゃほにゃうーにゃーにゃー！
Miko miko miko, honyahonya, uu nyanya!
さくらくるくるり さくらみこ
Sakura, spinning round and round, Sakura Miko!
みこみこみこで むにゃむにゃぐーぐーぐー
Miko miko miko, munyamunya, gu gu gu!
明日から本気出す！
Starting tomorrow, I'll get serious!
みこみこみこで ほにゃほにゃうーにゃーにゃー！
Miko miko miko, honyahonya, uu nyanya!
金時はほにゃうにゃにゃ たぶん
Kintoki is honyau nyanya, probably.
幸せの太鼓 ポンポコリン リンリン！
The drum of happiness goes ponpokorin, ring ring!
みんな笑顔になあれ！
May everyone be filled with smiles!
わんつーで参戦！
One, two, enlist!
みこみこみこ！
Miko miko miko!
ちょっとだけ休憩タイム
Just a little break time.
マイペースだけど許してね！
Forgive me for being at my own pace!
実はこれも修行のうちです
Actually, this is part of my training too.
そんなわけは…なくなくない！？
There's no way... or is there?!
あっバレたーっ！
Ah, I've been found out!
わたしはそうエリート！
I am so elite!
嘘じゃないよエリート！
It's not a lie, elite!
エリート巫女！？ エリートアイドル！？
Elite shrine maiden?! Elite idol?!
今日もがんばっ！張っていきましょう！
Let's do our best today too!
ココロ模様 曇り空 雨の日も？
Even on cloudy or rainy days in our hearts?
問題ない 巫女パワーで
No problem with shrine maiden power,
それ天晴れパレード！騒いじゃおうよ！
it's a sunny-weather parade! Let's get rowdy!
みこみこみこで ほにゃほにゃうーにゃーにゃー！
Miko miko miko, honyahonya, uu nyanya!
さくらくるくるり さくらみこ
Sakura, spinning round and round, Sakura Miko!
みこみこみこで むにゃむにゃぐーぐーぐー
Miko miko miko, munyamunya, gu gu gu!
たい焼きめでたい焼き
Taiyaki, delicious taiyaki!
みこみこみこで ほにゃほにゃうーにゃーにゃー！
Miko miko miko, honyahonya, uu nyanya!
カミサマもほにゃうにゃにゃ たぶん
Even the gods are honyau nyanya, probably.
元気の呪文 巫女巫女舞舞舞！
The cheer spell: miko miko mai mai mai!
みんな笑顔になあれ！
May everyone be filled with smiles!
にゃっはろー！ みんな楽しめる？
Nyahallo! Can everyone enjoy this?
ここからはスーパーみこみこタイム！
From here on is Super Miko Miko Time!
ぜったいに遅れずにつけてきてね！
Make sure you keep up without falling behind!
みんなで一緒にお手手を拝借！
Everyone, lend me your hands together!
はいっ！ みーこみーこ！
Ready? Miko miko!
みこはエリート！ e-l-i-t-e
Miko is elite! E-L-I-T-E
エリートエリート イエーイ！
Elite elite, yeah!
ラストもう一回 張り切って行くよーっ！
One last time, let's go with full energy!
ああっ あ ああ
Ah, ah, ah...
言いかけた言葉を飲み込んで
Swallowing the words I almost said,
あれっ 不具合(バグ)かな ストップしちゃってさ
Huh, is it a glitch? It just stopped,
何も言わなくたってキミは
Even if you say nothing at all,
なんだってわかってくれるけど
You understand everything, but...
カッコつけてもつかなくて
Even when I try to look cool, it doesn't work out,
失敗ばかりでごめんね
Sorry for making so many mistakes.
だけど言いたいことがあるの
Still, there's something I want to say:
もうちょっと あとちょっと
Just a little more, just a little bit more,
強くなりたいな
I want to become stronger.
キミのためならね
If it's for your sake.
ハートオンライン 気持ちまるごと
Heart Online, all of my feelings
乗せる電波 伝わるかな?
Loaded onto the radio waves, will they reach you?
大好きだって 大切だって
I want to say I love you, I care about you,
ホントはいつも言いたいのに
Even though I always want to say it...
きっと ねえ きっと 会えなくても
Surely, hey, surely even if we can't meet,
キミとだから繋がれるよ
I can connect with you because it's you.
ひらひらと舞う キミがくれた
Fluttering and dancing, the hearts you gave me
ハートが集まって
gather together
さくらになる
and become cherry blossoms.
分岐ルートで戸惑うたび
Whenever I hesitate at branching routes,
正解なんてわかんないけど
I don't know what the right answer is, but
一緒に探し当てた今日に
Today, which we found together,
いつも胸がいっぱいになるの
Always fills my heart to the brim.
ひとりだけ立ち止まってる
Even on nights when I felt like
そんな気がしてた夜にも
I was the only one standing still,
キミが見せてくれた景色に
In the scenery you showed me,
もう一歩 あと一歩
One more step, just one more step,
踏み出してみてみたいな
I want to try taking a step forward.
そう思えたんだ
That's what I came to feel.
ぜんぶオンライン ダメなところも
All online, even my useless parts
キミなら笑ってくれるよね?
You'd smile at them, right?
着飾るよりも ありのままで
Rather than dressing up, just as I am,
そんな勇気をくれたから
Because you gave me that courage,
きっと ねえ きっと くじけそうでも
Surely, hey, surely even if I feel discouraged,
何度だって花開くよ
Flowers will bloom over and over again.
ひらひらと舞う キミがくれた
Fluttering and dancing, the hearts you gave me
ハートが集まって
gather together
さくらになる
and become cherry blossoms.
舞い降りて 雨に流れる
Fluttering down, washing away in the rain,
そんな一瞬のユメでも
Even in such a fleeting dream,
睫毛の先ふわり 触れて
Gently brushing against the tips of my eyelashes,
煌めいた キミがいた
You were there, shining brightly.
さくら色の今が宝物だから
Because this cherry-blossom colored present is my treasure.
はーい、ということで、始まりました！さくらみこ4周年ライブ、ベイビーダンスライブ！
Hi everyone! And so, it has begun! Sakura Miko's 4th Anniversary Live, Baby Dance Live!
いやーちょっと初手でなんかトラブルがあって開始遅れちゃいましたけど！
Man, we had some trouble right at the start and it got a bit delayed, but!
まあこれもさくらみこらしいのかな、しょうがないのかな、今度の類いなのかなっていう感じですけど。
Well, I guess this is typical of Sakura Miko, or maybe it couldn't be helped, or just part of my usual routine.
皆さん楽しんでますか？みこぴー見てるー？
Are you all having fun? Mikopi, are you watching?
見て見て、こちらですね、じゃん！
Look, look, over here, ta-da!
今回のライブのロゴをね、このTシャツにプリントしてもらったんだよ。めちゃくちゃ可愛くない？ライぶっぽくない？いぇーい！
They printed the logo for this live on this T-shirt! Isn't it super cute? Doesn't it look like a live merch shirt? Yay!
かわいい！はい、
Cute! Yes,
ということで、今回のライブのハッシュタグは、こちら！
so the hashtag for this live is right here!
えーさくらみこ4周年、こちらね、
Uh, #SakuraMiko4thAnniversary, please...
たくさんつぶやいてトレンドにしてね！
tweet a lot and make it trend!
ありがとうね、みんな！はい、というわけで、まだまだまだまだ続きますから！
Thank you everyone! Alright, so there's still a lot more to come!
みんな盛り上がっていこう！いぇーい！
Let's all get hyped! Yay!
ありがとうね、みんな！
Thank you everyone!
まだまだまだまだ続きますから、みんな盛り上がっていこう！いぇーい！
It's still going to keep going, so let's all get even more hyped! Yay!
新のスカート 風に揺らして
Fluttering my new skirt in the wind,
立ち向かった難題を前に
Facing the difficult problems head-on,
微笑み戦うガール 真っ直ぐ進みたいと飛び出せど
A girl smiling and fighting, leaping out to go straight ahead,
歪みくねっていく僕らの不器用を 笑い飛ばしてみたいのさ
Wanting to laugh away our twisting, clumsy awkwardness.
迷いを纏い 傷を背負い 弱くて美しい 君と共に
Clad in hesitation, carrying scars, together with you,
明日へ向かう ah
Heading towards tomorrow, ah...
ねじこぼれた自由を歌え 手にあるもの全てで踊ろうぜ
Sing of the spilled-out freedom, let's dance with everything we hold in our hands.
問題は何もない ただこの道を照らすだけ
There are no problems at all, we just illuminate this path.
ah ねじこぼれた自由を歌え 手にあるもの以外は何もないぜ
Ah, sing of the spilled-out freedom, we have nothing other than what's in our hands.
喜びで愛しさで 恐れを今破壊せよ
With joy and affection, shatter your fears right now.
ジュースに溶かして後悔を吟味し 準備済ませたら今日の場所まで
Dissolving regret in juice and savoring it, once ready, heading to today's place.
電車に乗ってよろける足を 少しだけ踏み締めて 窓の上を見上げた
Riding the train, stepping firmly with wobbly legs, I looked up outside the window.
期待を抱え 夢を見る 擦り剥いた手の平で
Embracing expectations, dreaming with scraped palms,
僕ら 下手くそでも 明日を選ぶ ah
Even if we're clumsy, we choose tomorrow, ah.
下から上に育って行け 花の様に天へ伸ばす背骨
Growing from bottom to top, stretching our spines to the sky like flowers.
人波に揺れ 上手には歩けなくても ah
Rocked by the crowds, even if we can't walk skillfully, ah.
あちらこちらで光っている目に 立ち竦んで俯く日もあっていい
It's okay to stand paralyzed and look down at the lights shining everywhere.
驚きや喪失の その全てを記録せよ
Record all of the surprises and losses.
蹲って色付いた 癖 撫でた 愛でた
Crouching down, coloring, patting and cherishing our habits.
二人 向かい風の中入った 入口が出口だった
The two of us entered into the headwind, where the entrance was the exit.
ねじこぼれた自由を歌え 手にあるもの全てで踊ろうぜ
Sing of the spilled-out freedom, let's dance with everything we hold in our hands.
問題は何もない ただこの道を照らすだけ
There are no problems at all, we just illuminate this path.
ah ねじこぼれた自由を歌え 手にあるもの以外は何もないぜ
Ah, sing of the spilled-out freedom, we have nothing other than what's in our hands.
喜びで愛しさで 恐れを今破壊せよ
With joy and affection, shatter your fears right now.
Going, going, going...
あぁ
Ah...
言いかけた言葉を飲み込んで
Swallowing the words I started to say,
あれっ 不具合(バグ)かな ストップしちゃってさ
Ah, is there a glitch? It stopped completely.
何も言わなくたってキミは
Even if I don't say anything, you
なんでもわかってくれるけどさ
understand everything, but...
カッコ付けてもつかなくて
Even when I try to look cool, it doesn't work out,
失敗ばかりでごめんね
I'm sorry for always messing up.
だけど言いたいことがあるよ
Yet, there's something I want to tell you:
もうちょっと あとちょっと
Just a little bit more, just a little bit more,
強くなりたいな
I want to become stronger,
キミのためならね
If it's for you...
ハートオンライン 気持ちまるごと
Heart Online, loading all my feelings,
乗せる電波 伝わるかな？
Will this transmission reach you?
大好きだって 大切だって
"I love you so much," "You're so precious to me,"
ホントはいつも言いたいのにさ
Even though I always want to say it truly...
きっと ねぇ きっと 会えなくても
I'm sure, hey, I'm sure, even if we can't meet,
キミとだから繋がれるよ
It's because it's you that we can stay connected.
ひらひらと舞う
Fluttering and dancing,
キミがくれたハートが集まって
The hearts you gave me gather together
さくらになる
And become cherry blossoms.
分岐ルートで戸惑うたび
Every time I get lost on a branching route,
正解なんてわかんないけどさ
I never know what the right answer is, but...
一緒に探し当てた今日にさ
My heart is always so full
いつも胸がいっぱいになるの
For the "today" we found together.
ひとりだけ立ち止まってる
On nights when I felt like
そんな気がしてた夜にもさ
I was the only one standing still,
キミが見せてくれた景色に
In the scenery you showed me,
もう一歩 あと一歩
One more step, just one more step,
踏み出してみたいな
I wanted to try stepping forward—
そう思えたんだ
That's what I came to think.
ぜんぶ オンライン ダメなところも
All online, even my clumsy parts,
キミなら笑ってくれるよね？
You'd smile at them, right?
着飾るよりも ありのままで
Rather than dressing up, just being my true self,
そんな勇気をくれたからさ
Because you gave me that courage.
きっと ねぇ きっと 挫れそうでも
I'm sure, hey, I'm sure, even if I'm about to break,
何度だって花開くよ
Flowers will bloom over and over again.
ひらひらと舞う
Fluttering and dancing,
キミがくれたハートが集まって
The hearts you gave me gather together
さくらになる
And become cherry blossoms.
舞い落ちて 雨に流れる
Falling down and washing away in the rain,
そんな瞬間のメロディでも
Even in such a fleeting dream,
睫毛の先ふわり 触れて
Gently touching the tip of my eyelashes,
煌めいた キミがいた
There was you, shining brightly.
さくら色のいまが 宝物だから
Because the cherry-blossom-colored "now" is my treasure.
さぁさぁ始まりました高校生活
Now, now, high school life has begun!
はたしてハッピーエンドで終わるのでしょうか
Will it end with a happy ending, I wonder?
もしも彼氏なんてできちゃったり!?
Could I even get a boyfriend?!
JKライフ謳歌せよ
Time to fully enjoy the JK life!
もう全然ダメダメ テスト勉強
Studying for tests is already totally hopeless!
数学なんて使わないじゃん微分積分
We never use math like differential and integral calculus anyway!
なんとかなっしー!必殺一夜漬けでね
It'll work out somehow! The ultimate all-nighter!
笑顔で乗り切れ3人娘
Get through it with smiles, you trio of girls!
ハレバレ!
Feeling bright and clear!
ご褒美はスイーツ
The reward is sweets!
ライブも行きたいな
I want to go to a live concert, too!
お泊り会して恋バナ
Having a slumber party and talking about love,
秘密なしだからね!
No secrets allowed between us, okay?!
Foo!
ヒロインJK目指せ
Aiming to be the heroine JK!
モジモジしてらんない
Can't afford to be all shy and hesitant!
モブなんじゃいられない
Can't just stay as a background mob character!
好きなことで進め
Advance with the things you love!
後悔なんてしない
No regrets allowed!
我慢なんて勿体ない
Holding back is such a waste!
期待のJKなのです
We're promising high school girls, after all!
ハラハラしてください
Please be thrilled and nervous!
優等生じゃいられない
Can't be honor students all the time!
言いたいことは言って
Say whatever you want to say!
やりたいことはやって
Do whatever you want to do!
我慢なんてしてらんない
Can't just hold everything back!
JKライフ謳歌せよ
Time to fully enjoy the JK life!
テストも終わった打ち上げだー!
The tests are over, time for the celebration party!
カラオケ行こう!
Let's go to karaoke!
いいね!金は合わせの手たろむ!
Sounds great! Hey, handle the cheering chants!
OK!
推し曲ロメオデュエット
Our favorite song's Romeo duet.
「さあおいで」「ちょ!ちょ!」
"Now come here." "Wait! Wait!"
放課後全力3人娘
The after-school all-out trio of girls!
ハレバレ!
Feeling bright and clear!
のろけ話聞いて
Listen to my boastful love stories,
バイト愚痴も聞いて
Listen to my complaints about part-time jobs, too!
お泊り会して夜更かし
A slumber party and staying up late,
Calorie解放日! yeah!
Calorie liberation day! Yeah!
ヒロインJKなって
Becoming heroine JKs,
モテ期で悩みたぃ
Wanting to worry about being too popular!
かませ犬じゃいられない
Can't be just stepping stones for others!
ネガティブなんてポイで
Throw away all the negativity!
ポジティブ抱きしめて
Embrace positivity!
青春するの
Living our youth to the fullest!
照れないでルーキーJKなのです
Don't be shy, we're rookie JKs!
先輩達にも負けない
We won't lose to the seniors either!
苦手もちょっと挑戦
Take on a bit of what we're bad at, too!
大好きもっと磨け
Polish what we love even more!
芋女って言わせない!
Don't you dare call us unstylish country girls!
友達だよね 当たり前っしょ
We're friends, right? Obviously!
お泊り会してパーティ!
A slumber party and a party!
秘密なしだからね! Foo!
No secrets allowed, okay? Foo!
ヒロインJK目指せ
Aiming to be the heroine JK!
モジモジしてらんない
Can't afford to be all shy and hesitant!
モブなんじゃいられない
Can't just stay as a background mob character!
好きなことで進め
Advance with the things you love!
後悔なんてしない
No regrets allowed!
我慢なんて勿体ない
Holding back is such a waste!
期待のJKなのです
We're promising high school girls, after all!
優等生じゃいられない
Can't be honor students all the time!
言いたいことは言って
Say whatever you want to say!
やりたいことはやって
Do whatever you want to do!
我慢なんてしてらんない
Can't just hold everything back!
JKライフ謳歌せよ
Time to fully enjoy the JK life!
あっちわ こいして
Ah, I want you!
こっちわ ほしくて
Ah, I want you to want me!
あっちわ こいして
Ah, I want you!
こっちわ ほしくて
Ah, I want you to want me!
あっちわ ほしくて
Ah, I want you!
こっちわ ほしいの
Ah, I want you to want me!
あっちわ ほしくて
Ah, I want you!
はらほろひれはれ
Ah, I want you to want me!
知ってる 自由を探すことなんていまさら
I know, searching for freedom now
バカげてる
is just ridiculous,
隣のカゴに飛び移った 鳥みたいじゃない
like a bird jumping into the next cage.
知ってる どうやったってどこにでもあるよな
I know, however you look at it, it's everywhere—
理想・拝・つまり全身全霊の今は嘘なんかじゃない
Ideal, worship... meaning my wholehearted present is no lie!
ないから
Because it's not!
生まれ落ちた ぷかぷか でも出れない
Born floating, yet unable to escape,
このままホライゾン 稼いできても 望むよ
even if I keep earning horizons just like this, I yearn—
薬に背を向けた 穴よけの
for the trap-avoiding path that turned its back on medicine,
行方知らずのドードーは
the whereabouts-unknown dodo is...
我が儘 姫君 ああ 可哀想
A selfish princess, oh, how pitiful!
シーシーシー はいっ！
Shh-shh-shh, hey!
今日からキミの好きなとこ 一日一個伝えよう
Starting today, I'll tell you one thing I like about you every day!
365回ドキドキさせちゃうで バッキューン！
Making your heart race 365 times, bang!
小悪魔だってかまわない！
Even if I'm a little devil, I don't care!
こっちにおいでよもう もしかしてまだ片思い？
Come over here already... Could it be that it's still unrequited love?
たまに甘えてくるくせに もしかしてこの僕が狙ってる？
Even though you act all sweet sometimes, could it be that you're aiming for me?
ひとめぼれして 毎日通ってた
Falling in love at first sight, I visited every day
キミと目が合うたびに 恋が爆発
Every time our eyes meet, love explodes!
今日からキミの好きなとこ 一日一個伝えよう
Starting today, I'll tell you one thing I like about you every day!
365回ドキドキさせちゃうで バッキューン！
Making your heart race 365 times, bang!
ほかの女の子なんて 目にも入れない
Not even looking at other girls,
携帯画面たり キミだけに見せるよ
I'll only show you on my phone screen!
えらいのがほめは… きゅん！
Praise me, what a good boy... Kyun!
たまにはお出かけしよう いつも部屋でトマカリンじゃん
Let's go out once in a while! We're always playing games in my room.
もちろんそれでもいいけど ボクだってオシャレしたいし
Of course, even that's fine, but I want to dress up nicely too!
昼間なら二人でお手て繋げるな
In broad daylight, we could hold hands, you know.
ボクはいまひとりと なにもできないくせに
Right now I'm all alone, even though I can't do anything on my own.
毎日キミの機嫌とって 一日いっぱいハグして
Pleasing your mood every day, hugging you all day long,
なんて言わないから 愛を伝えてちょうだい バッキューン！
I won't say things like that, so just convey your love to me! Bang!
ひとり占めしたがり ゲームばっかりしてないで
Wanting to keep you all to yourself, stop playing games all the time!
キミだけに見せるよ えらいのがほめは きゅん！
I'll only show you! Praise me, what a good boy! Kyun!
帰り遅くなりそうだけど 急いで帰るからね
I might be coming home a little late, but I'll rush back home, so—
寄り道せずに逢いに来ます
I'll come meet you without making any detours!
ただいま！
I'm home!
お帰りのなし 上手よしのなし
No welcome home? Good boy, bad boy...
それでもいいよ だから 一緒に見てね
Even so, that's fine too, so let's watch together.
ねえねえどこ隠れてるの もしかして照れちゃった？
Hey hey, where are you hiding? Could it be you got shy?
急に飛び込んできた 君は小悪魔だね
You suddenly jumped out at me, you little devil.
今日からキミの好きなとこ 一日一個伝えよう
Starting today, I'll tell you one thing I like about you every day!
365回ドキドキさせちゃうで バッキューン！
Making your heart race 365 times, bang!
ほかの女の子なんて 目にも入れない
Not even looking at other girls,
キミだけに見せるよ えらいのがほめは きゅん！
I'll only show you! Praise me, what a good boy! Kyun!
今となれば名残り雪
Now that it's time, the lingering snow
虫は歩くよいよにと
Insects walk, saying 'yo yo'
限りあるものが歌う
Limited things sing
眠り冬を越えて
Crossing the winter sleep
待ち遠しいや 梅 桜 花見月
Waiting so long for plum and cherry blossoms
匂えば蝶に蜜蜂が舞う
Butterflies and bees dance to the fragrance
少女名月はよ起きんかな
Maiden, is it time to wake up?
今はただ陽光に誰が夢を描く
Now just in the sunlight, who paints dreams?
さあさ もっと踊れや踊れ
Come on, dance more and more
晩まで鳴らすこ鳴らせ
Until night, play the naruko
花吹雪 咲かせや咲かせ
Petals in a blizzard, bloom, oh bloom
新しき 春の日来れば
When the new spring day comes
雪解けて 土匂えば
Snow melts, earth smells fragrant
蛙も鳴くげらげらと
Frogs croak, laughing out loud
草は芽吹き 山笑う
Grass sprouts, mountains laugh
眠り冬を越えて
Crossing the winter sleep
調子良りゃえさほいさ そこの集
If you're in high spirits, eisa hoisa
負けたらそれの御目々踊るまで
Drink until your eyes spin if you lose
しょうじょうぜいぜいあらずしらんこと
Whatever it is, who knows
今はただはなむけとみな夢を描く
Now just as a farewell gift, everyone paints dreams
さあさ もっといわえやいわえ
Come on, praise more and more
晩まで祭あかばせ
Until night, hold a festival
皆囲め 咲かせや咲かせ
Everyone gather around, bloom, oh bloom
新しき 春の日来れば
When the new spring day comes
心もまたいぶく
Hearts will throb once more
どんと言騒げ お前が立て役者
Make some noise, you're the leading actor
踊るあほうに見るあほう
Dancing fools, watching fools
感謝感謝でやってたき拍子に乗れ
Hit them thankfully, ride the rhythm
うんとも騒げ 天地地上まで震わぜよ
Make some noise, shake the earth up to heaven
どんと言騒げ 老も若きもそいやと
Make some noise, young and old alike
さあさ もっと踊れや踊れ
Come on, dance more and more
晩まで鳴らすこ鳴らせ
Until night, play the naruko
花吹雪 咲かせや咲かせ
Petals in a blizzard, bloom, oh bloom
新しき 春の日来れば
Come, new spring day
さあさ もっといわえやいわえ
Come on, praise more and more
晩まで祭あかばせ
Until night, hold a festival
皆囲め 咲かせや咲かせ
Everyone gather around, bloom, oh bloom
新しき 春の日来れば
When the new spring day comes
さあさ もっといわえやいわえ
Come on, praise more and more
晩まで祭あかばせ
Until night, hold a festival
皆囲め 咲かせや咲かせ
Everyone gather around, bloom, oh bloom
新しき 春の日来れば
When the new spring day comes
心もまたいぶく
Hearts will throb once more
咲かせや咲かせ
Bloom, oh bloom
目覚めては繰り返す
On a sleepy morning
眠い朝は
that I keep on waking up to
襟のタイをきつく締め
I pull my necktie tight with both hands
教室のドアくぐるとうほんの少し胸を張って歩き出せる
Stepping out through the classroom door with pride
そんな日常に吹き抜ける風
A breeze blowing through such ordinary days
聞こえた気がした
I realized that I heard it
感じた気がしたんだ
I realized I felt it already
震え出す今この胸で
Now in my chest that starts to tremble
もう来る気がした
I realized it was coming
幾億の星が消えてくのを
I saw off the millions of stars disappearing
見送った
I waved my hand
手を振った
Saying goodbye
よかったね、と
Saying 'good for you'
廊下の隅見下ろす 掃除の途中
Looking down from the hallway while cleaning
おかしいものだと思う
I think it is really a very strange thing
あしたの中の時は止まってるのに
Even though time inside has stopped
違う日々を生きてるように
It feels like living through different days
塵は雪のように降り積もる
Dust falls and piles like white snow
待ってる気がした 呼んでる気がしたんだ
It feels like you're waiting and calling
震え出す今この時間が
Now in this time that starts to tremble
目覚めては繰り返す 眠い朝は
On a sleepy morning when I just fall asleep and wake
襟のタイをきつく締め
I fasten my necktie tightly
教室のドアくぐるとほんの少し胸を張って歩き出せる
Able to stick out my chest ever so slightly
そんな日常に吹き抜ける風
The wind blows right through such ordinary days
聞こえた気がした
I felt like I heard it
感じた気がしたんだ 震え出す今この胸で
Because I felt like I sensed it, just now...
もう来る気がした
I felt it come again
幾億の星が消えていくのを
Some hundred million stars vanishing...
見送った 手を振った
I saw them off, waved goodbye
よかったね、と
And said "good for you"
廊下の隅見下ろす 掃除の途中
While cleaning I looked down into the corner
おかしなものだと思う
And thought that it really was strange
あたしの中の時は止まっているのに
Even though the time inside of me has stopped
違う日々を生きてるように
I feel like each day I live is different
埃は雪のように降り積もる
And dust piles up like snow
待ってる気がした
I felt like it was waiting for me
呼んでる気がしたんだ
Because I felt like it was calling to me
震え出す今この時が見つけた気がした
Just now, this time that has begun to tremble
失われた記憶が呼び覚ました
The memories I lost were awoken
物語 永遠のその終わり
This is the end of my eternal story
いつの間にか駆け出していた
Before I knew it I took off running
あなたに手を引かれていた
Pulled along by your hand
昨日は遠く 明日はすぐ
Yesterday so distant and tomorrow so close
そんな当たり前に心が躍った
Naturally, it made my heart leap
聞こえた気がした
I felt like I heard it
感じた気がしたんだ 震え出す今この胸で
Because I felt like I sensed it, just now...
もう来る気がした
I felt it come again
幾千の朝を越え 新しい陽が
The new sun crossing over a thousand mornings
待ってる気がした
I felt like it was waiting for me
呼んでる気がしたんだ
Because I felt like it was calling to me
震えてるこの魂が見つけた気がした
My shivering spirit, I felt like I had found it
幾億の夢のように消え去る日を
These days that could vanish like some hundred million dreams
見送った 手を振った
I saw them off, waved goodbye
ありがとう、と
And said "thank you"
辺りは同じ色
At the same color around
違う色は指をさされていた
Different colors were pointed at
怖くて隠してた
Scared and hidden
同じ色になりかけていた
I was starting to become the same color
明日 好きから逃げるなよ
Tomorrow, don't run away from what you love
胸を張って輝け
Stick out your chest and shine
世界は広いよ見てごらんよ
The world is vast, go take a look
僕ら わがまま育てて
We grow our selfishness
媚びず夢を貫け
Stay unyielding to your dreams without fawning
ネガティブな自分置いていこう
Let's leave our negative selves behind
君の色が綺麗でたった一つで
Your color is beautiful, and it's the only one
世界を彩っている花みたいで
Like a flower painting the world in color
ほら 照れないでいいんだよ顔上げて
Hey, don't be shy, lift up your head
特別な君でいて
Stay as your special self
やりたい事やらなきゃ損じゃん?
Isn't it a loss if you don't do what you want to do?
選手宣誓
Oath of athletes!
他人の夢それじゃダメ!君を楽しめ
Someone else's dream? That won't do! Enjoy yourself
見た目も違うのに
Even though we look different
同じレール歩かなくちゃダメなの?
Do we have to walk on the same rails?
“恥ずかしい”夢だって
Even "embarrassing" dreams...
胸の隅に追いやっていていた
Were pushed away into the corner of my heart
いつか 好きは錆びついてて
Someday, love rusts away
忘れ去られてなくなって
And becomes forgotten and gone
そんなの嘘だよ ずーっといるよ 今も
That's a lie, it's always here, even now
ワクワクになれる
Able to get excited
夢が胸支配して
Dreams dominate my heart
時間さえ忘れ笑っている
Even forgetting time as I smile
辺りは同じ色 違う色は指をさされていた
The surroundings were the same color, different colors were pointed at
怖くて隠してて 同じ色になりかけていた
I was scared and hiding, trying to become the same color
明日
Tomorrow,
好きから逃げないで 胸を張って輝け
don't run away from what you love, hold your head high and shine
世界は広いよ
The world is wide,
見てごらんよ
take a look!
僕ら
We,
わがまま育てて 媚びず夢を貫け
nurturing our selfishness, pierce through our dreams without flattering
ネガティブな自分置いていこう
Let's leave our negative selves behind
君の色彩が綺麗でだった一つで世界を彩っている花みたいで
Your color is beautiful, like a single flower coloring the world
ほら照れないでいいんだよ顔上げて
Hey, don't be shy, raise your head
特別な君でいて
and be a special you
やりたい事やらなきゃ損しちゃう？選手宣誓 他人の夢 それじゃダメ！
Isn't it a loss if you don't do what you want to do? Athlete's oath! Someone else's dream? That won't do!
君を楽しめ
Enjoy yourself
見た目も違うのに 同じレール歩かなくちゃダメなの？
Even though our appearances are different, do we have to walk the same rail?
“恥ずかしい”夢だって 胸の隅に追いやっていた
"Embarrassing" dreams were pushed to the corner of my heart
いつか好きは錆びつき去って忘れ去られ無くなる
Someday, love will rust and be forgotten
そんなの嘘だよ
That's a lie,
ずっといるよ
it will always be here
今もワクワクになれる 夢が胸支配して 時間さえ忘れ笑っている
Even now, dreams that make me excited dominate my heart, forgetting even time and smiling
君の色は名前なんてなくて見とれてる
Your color has no name, I'm captivated,
世界輝かせてる星みたいで
like a star making the world shine
合わなくてもいいんだよそのままで 特別な君でいて
You don't need to conform, just stay as you are, be a special you
楽しいこと待ってちゃ損しちゃう？ 迎えにいこう
Isn't it a loss to wait for fun things? Let's go meet them
君の一歩 君が踏み出せ！
Your first step, you take it!
夢を楽しめ
Enjoy your dreams
明日 死んでしまっても後悔はしないように 過ごしていませんか？ 胸に聞いて
Even if you die tomorrow, are you spending it so you won't have regrets? Ask your heart
僕ら “好き”をするために 笑い合う日のために
We, to do what we love, for the days we laugh together,
生きているんだよ 忘れないで
are living, don't forget it
届け
Deliver it
君の色が綺麗でだった一つで世界彩っている花みたいで
Your color is beautiful, like a single flower coloring the world
ほら照れないでいいんだよ顔上げて
Hey, don't be shy, raise your head
特別な君でいて
and be a special you
やりたい事やらなきゃ損しちゃう？選手宣誓 他人の夢 それじゃダメ！
Isn't it a loss if you don't do what you want to do? Athlete's oath! Someone else's dream? That won't do!
君を楽しめ
Enjoy yourself
がんばっている君に 捧げる夢ファンファーレ
A dream fanfare dedicated to you who is doing your best
雨上がりの虹も 凛と咲いた花も
The rainbow after the rain and the flowers blooming with dignity
色づき溢れ出す
Overflow with colors
茜色の空仰ぐ君に あの日恋に落ちた
I fell in love with you that day as you looked up at the crimson sky
瞬間のドラマティック フィルムの中の1コマも 消えないよ 心に刻むから
Not even a single frame from the dramatic film of that moment will fade away, because I'll engrave it in my heart
君だよ 君なんだよ 教えてくれた
It's you, it's you who taught me
闇夜も光るなら 星空になる
If the darkness can shine, it will become a starry sky
悲しみを笑顔に もう隠さないで
Don't hide your sadness behind a smile anymore
煌めくどんな星も 君を照らすから
Every sparkling star will shine on you
眠りも忘れて迎えた朝日が やたらと突き刺さる
The morning sun I welcomed forgetting to sleep pierces me so much
低気圧運ぶ 頭痛だって 忘れる 君に会えば
I forget even the headache brought by low pressure when I see you
静寂はロマンティック 紅茶に溶けた砂糖のように 全身に巡るよ 君の声
Silence is romantic, your voice flows through my body like sugar melting in black tea
君だよ 君なんだよ 笑顔をくれた
It's you, it's you who gave me a smile
涙も光るなら 流星になる
If my tears also shine, they will turn into shooting stars
傷付いたその手を もう離さないで
Don't let go of my wounded hand anymore
願いを込めた空に 明日が来るから
Tomorrow will come to the sky filled with wishes
導いてくれた 光は 君だよ
The light that guided me was you
つられて僕も 走り出した
I was drawn in and started running too
知らぬ間に クロスし始めた
Before I knew it, we started crossing paths
ほら 今だ ここで 光るなら
Look, now, if it shines here
君だよ 君なんだよ 教えてくれた
It's you, it's you who taught me
暗闇は終わるから
The darkness will end
君だよ 君なんだよ 教えてくれた
It's you, it's you who taught me
闇夜も光るなら 星空になる
If the darkness can shine, it will become a starry sky
悲しみを笑顔に もう隠さないで
Don't hide your sadness behind a smile anymore
煌めくどんな星も 君を照らすから
Every sparkling star will shine on you
眠りも忘れて 迎えた朝日が
The morning sun I welcomed forgetting to sleep
やたらと突き刺さる
pierces me so much
繋がって 僕も走り出した
Connected, I started running too
知らぬ間に
Before I knew it,
黒酢し始めた 君に会えば
crossing paths when I meet you
静寂はロマンティック
Silence is romantic
紅茶に溶けた砂糖のように 全身に巡るよ
like sugar melting in black tea flowing through my body
君の声
your voice
君だよ 君なんだよ
It's you, it's you
笑顔をくれた 涙も光るなら
who gave me a smile, if my tears also shine
流星になる 傷付いたその手を
they will turn into shooting stars, don't let go
もう離さないで 願いを込めた空に
of my wounded hand anymore, to the sky filled with wishes
明日が来るから
tomorrow will come
導いてくれた 光は君だよ
The light that guided me was you
釣られて 僕も走り出した
I was drawn in and started running too
知らぬ間に クロスし始めた
Before I knew it, we started crossing paths
ほら 今だ ここで 光るなら
Look, now, if it shines here
君だよ 君なんだよ 教えてくれた
It's you, it's you who taught me
暗闇は終わるから
The darkness will end
君だよ 君なんだよ 教えてくれた
It's you, it's you who taught me
闇夜も光るなら 星空になる
If the darkness can shine, it will become a starry sky
悲しみを笑顔に もう隠さないで
Don't hide your sadness behind a smile anymore
煌めくどんな星も 君を照らすから
Every sparkling star will shine on you
答えはいつでも 偶然？必然？
Is the answer always coincidence? Or fate?
いつか選んだ道こそ 運命になる
Someday the path we choose will become our destiny
雨上がりの虹も
The rainbow after the rain,
凛と咲いた花も
the flowers blooming with dignity,
色づき溢れ出る
overflowing with color.
茜色の空仰ぐ君に
I looked up at you in the crimson sky,
あの日恋に落ちた
and fell in love with you that day.
瞬間のドラマティック
The dramatic moment...
君だよ 君なんだよ
It's you, it's you
教えてくれた
who taught me.
闇も光るなら 星空になる
If the darkness shines, it becomes a starry sky.
悲しみを笑顔に もう隠さないで
Don't hide your sadness behind a smile anymore.
煌めくどんな星も 君を照らすから
Every sparkling star will shine upon you.
出会いはいつでも偶然 必然
Encounters are always coincidence or fate,
いつか選んだ道こそ運命になる
and the path we chose someday becomes our destiny.
握りしめたその希望も不安も
The hopes and anxieties we clutched tightly
きっと二人を動かす光になるから
will surely become the light that moves us both.
光るなら 星空になる
If it shines, it becomes a starry sky.
はい、という事で！ え、なんと白銀メンバーに歌ってもらいました！
Yes, and so! We had Shirogane-gumi sing for us!
イェーイ！ お疲れ様！
Yay! Great job!
いや、すごいな！
Man, that was amazing!
え、ちょっとじゃあ社長はこちらに...
Um, President, please come over here...
イェーイ！ どうだった？
Yay! How was it?
いやあ、緊張した...！
Man, I was so nervous...!
今何も決めてなかったから...一緒に決めた方がいいよね
We hadn't decided anything yet... We should decide together.
はい、という事で！ ありがとうございます！
Yes, and so! Thank you very much!
あのさ、白銀でさ、衣装もさ、そろえようって
You know, for Shirogane, we wanted to match our outfits...
初めてだよね！
It's our first time!
ポーズも... ちょっとよく見せて、リボンのところとか！
Our poses... Show us closely, like the ribbon part!
かわいいね！ 揃えて...最初から揃えてた？
So cute! Did you match them from the beginning?
ペコラとポルコ、デザイン同じなの！
Pekora and Polka have the same design!
衣装一緒なんだ！ えーかわいい！
Your outfits are the same! Aww, cute!
えっ、ノエルとねねるは？ 違うねんか！
What about Noel and Neneru? They're different!
え、なんか違うね... 動揺がすごい！ 動きが！
Huh, they're different... Such shock! Their movements!
という事で、やっぱ撮影会会合しとー！
And so, after all, a photo session gathering—!
イェーイ！
Yay!
じゃあさ、ファンの皆とさ、一緒にさ、写真撮りたいな！
Then, we want to take a photo together with all the fans!
みんな、映ってる？
Everyone, are you in frame?
イェーイ！ かわいい！ イェーイ！
Yay! So cute! Yay!
みんな口開けてー！ どうだ！
Everyone open your mouths! How's that!
ボコ！ 社長真ん中だろ！
Boko! President is in the middle!
よし！ イェーイ！ みんなかぶってる！
Alright! Yay! Everyone's overlapping!
イェーイ！ イェーイ！ できてなーい！
Yay! Yay! It didn't work!
まわりまわり！ 回れ回れ！ イェーイ！
Spin around! Spin around! Yay!
ノエル、ノエル、ノエル... なんか寄ってるよ！
Noel, Noel, Noel... You're leaning in!
ありがとう！ 満足満足！
Thank you! Satisfied, satisfied!
わあ、びっくりした！ なんか出た！
Wow, I was surprised! Something popped out!
え、なになんだ！ なんかちっちゃくなってる！
Eh, what what? It's gotten smaller!
ねこみこ！ ねこみこやん！ 記念撮影しよ！
Nekomiko! It's Nekomiko! Let's take a photo!
ねこみこと一緒に記念撮影しよう！ 記念だからね！
Let's take a photo with Nekomiko! Because it's an anniversary!
ねこみこもいっぱいいっぱいスペシャルショットで！
Nekomiko too, with tons of special shots!
どこだろー？
Where is it?
おふとんしてねー
Tuck me in!
ここだよ！
Right here!
どこだろ？
Where is it?
みこ？みこここだよ！
Miko? Miko's right here!
ここだよー！
Right here!
自分らしってなんだ？
What is being yourself?
“人とは違う”で差をつけろ
Stand out by being "different from others."
コンビニの雑誌コーナー
At the convenience store's magazine corner,
表紙に太字で書いてあった
It was written in bold on the cover.
自分らしってなんだ？
What is being yourself?
子どもの頃は気にせず
In childhood, without a care,
気に入らなければ怒って
If you didn't like it, you'd get angry,
好きなものを好きだと言って
Saying you like what you like.
僕らは変わっていく
We are changing,
守りたいものが変わっていく
What we want to protect is changing.
理解されない宝物から
From treasures that are not understood
理解されるための建前へ
To the pretense of being understood.
大人になるほど
As we become adults,
後悔する生き物になる
We become creatures who regret.
でもね それでもね
But you know, even so,
見えるものがあるんだよ
There are things that can be seen.
だから僕は僕らしく
So I am me,
そして君は君らしくって
And you are you.
始めから探すようなものではないと思うんだ
I think it's not something you search for from the start.
僕は君じゃないし
I am not you,
君も僕じゃないから
And you are not me.
すれ違う 手を繋ぐ
Passing by, holding hands,
そこには愛だって生まれる
There is love born there.
そういうもんさ
That's how it is.
自分らしってなんだろう
What is being yourself?
変えられない
That cannot be changed,
大切があるから変わりゆく生活が正しい
Because there is something precious, a changing life is correct.
個性を出さなきゃいけない
You have to show your individuality,
そういう流行の無個性で
With that trendy lack of individuality.
悟ったように一歩引いた
Like you've figured it out, stepping back,
匿名希望の傍観者
An anonymous spectator.
ちょっと待ってよ星空は
Wait a moment, the starry sky
変わらずあの日と同じだよ
Is the same as that day, unchanged.
理解されずとも宝物は
Even if not understood, your treasures
今でも宝物のはずでしょう
Should still be treasures even now.
変化が怖くて変わらぬ日々も嫌で
Afraid of change, hating unchanging days,
変わりたくて変われなくて
Wanting to change, unable to change.
見失いそうで自分である意味とか
Feeling like you might lose the meaning of being yourself,
子どもの頃を思い出すりして
Thinking back to childhood.
見失いそうで自分である意味とか
Feeling like you might lose yourself,
コンビニで目にした太字を気にしてたんだろ
Worried about the bold text you saw at the convenience store.
でもね それでもね
But you know, even so,
見えるものに気づいてよ
Notice what you can see.
だから僕は僕らしく
So I am me,
そして君は君らしくって
And you are you.
始めから探すようなものではないと思うんだ
I think it's not something you search for from the start.
僕は君じゃないし
I am not you,
君も僕じゃないから
And you are not me.
すれ違う 手を繋ぐ
Passing by, holding hands,
そこには愛だって生まれる
There is love born there.
そういうもんさ
That's how it is.
自分らしってなんだろう
What is being yourself?
変えられない
That cannot be changed,
大切があるから
Because there is something precious,
変わりゆく生活が正しい
A changing life is correct.
変わらない
Because there is something precious
大切があるから
That remains unchanged...
絶対手は抜かない
Never cutting corners,
感謝を忘れない
Never forgetting to be grateful,
決して驕らない
Never becoming arrogant,
ここに誓います
I swear it here.
深い優しさを持って
Holding deep kindness,
強い信念を持って
Holding strong conviction,
誇り高きアイドル
A proud idol
目指してます
I'm aiming for the top.
でも女の子だから
But since I'm a girl,
泣いたりもする
I sometimes cry too.
ヤキモチだって妬くし
I get jealous too,
だから
So let me speak
本音を言うとね…
my true feelings...
推しにしてくれなくちゃ嫌だ
You better make me your oshi!
私以外を見ちゃ嫌だ
You can't look at anyone else!
推し変なんて許さない！
I'll never forgive an oshi-hen!
法律で決まってるの（嘘）
It's the law! (Just kidding)
お歌もダンスもちょっぴり
My singing and dancing
苦手だけど
Are a bit clumsy, but
誰より愛を持って
With more love than anyone else,
アイドルしてます！
I'm acting as an idol!
トップ目指して
Aiming for the top,
どんな新曲がいい？
What kind of new song do you want?
どんな衣装が見たい？
What kind of outfit do you want to see?
一緒に楽しみを分かち合いたいね
I want to share the fun together with you.
私は君のためにあって
I exist for your sake,
君は私のためにあって
And you exist for my sake.
そんな理想
Such an ideal
本気で目指してます
I'm seriously aiming for!
でも人は人を嫌って
But people hate each other
傷つけもする
And even hurt one another.
アンチだって怖いから
Haters are scary too,
だから本音を言わせて…
So let me speak my true feelings...
推しにしないと泣くから
If you don't make me your oshi, I'll cry,
ファンサだって頑張るから
So I'll work hard on fan service!
推し増ししてもいいから
It's okay to have multiple oshis,
ガッカリさせないでよね
But don't let me down, okay?
トークもぶりっ子もちょっぴり
My chatting and cutesy acts
苦手だけど
Are a bit clumsy, but
熱いプライドを持って
With a burning pride,
アイドルしてます！
I'm acting as an idol!
応援も厳しい言葉も
Both cheers and harsh words
愛の形 奮い立つんだ
Are forms of love that fire me up!
誰かを救うこの夢
This dream of saving someone,
全てを賭けるこの夢
This dream I'm betting everything on,
曇りなどない
Has not a single cloud,
快晴
Pure clear skies!
いつか飽きられたり
Even if one day I'm grown tired of
忘れられたり
Or forgotten,
仕方ない事だけど
I know it's inevitable, but—
だけどこれだけは聞いて
Please, just listen to this:
ずっと歌い続けるよ
I'll keep on singing forever,
ずっと踊り続けるよ
I'll keep on dancing forever.
辛いことがある日は
On days when things are tough,
たまに思い出してね
Remember me once in a while.
でもやっぱり…
But still...
推しにしてくれなくちゃ嫌だ
You better make me your oshi!
私以外を見ちゃ嫌だ
You can't look at anyone else!
推し変なんて許さない！
I'll never forgive an oshi-hen!
法律で決まってるの（嘘）
It's the law! (Just kidding)
お歌もダンスもちょっぴり苦手だけど
My singing and dancing are a bit clumsy, but
誰より愛を持ってアイドルしてます！
With more love than anyone else, I'm an idol!
トップ目指して
Aiming for the top,
厳しい言葉も
Even harsh words
愛の形
Are forms of love.
推しにしてくれなくちゃ嫌だ
You better make me your oshi!
私以外を見ちゃ嫌だ
You can't look at anyone else!
推し変なんて許さない！
I'll never forgive an oshi-hen!
法律で決まってるの（嘘）
It's the law! (Just kidding)
お歌もダンスもちょっぴり苦手だけど
My singing and dancing are a bit clumsy, but
誰より愛を持ってアイドルしてます！
With more love than anyone else, I'm an idol!
トップ目指して
Aiming for the top,
ずっと歌い続けるよ
I'll keep on singing forever!
はい、あ、あ、という事で！みんな楽しんでますかー！
Alright, um, so everyone, are you enjoying yourselves?!
はい、という事でいやあ、もう凄いのノンストップノンストップノンストップノンストップで！
Yes, so, wow, we delivered a totally non-stop, non-stop, non-stop show!
お届けしましたさくらみこ4周年！
This was Sakura Miko's 4th Anniversary!
ということで、もうね、もうすぐ終わりが近づいておるます。
And so, well, it's almost coming to an end.
え、皆さんに告知があります。もうみんながもうね分かってる告知からやっていこうと思います。
Um, I have an announcement for everyone! Let's start with the announcement you all probably already know.
みんなありがとうね、ありがとう！いや、普通にね、できてよかったよ。ありがとうね！
Thank you everyone, thank you! I'm so glad we were able to pull this off. Thank you!
それでは告知、どうぞ！
Now then, for the announcement, here it is!
はい、じゃじゃーん！こちらです！4周年ライブの裏側B2タペストリー！
Tada! Here it is! The "4th Anniversary Live Behind-the-Scenes" B2 Tapestry!
めちゃくちゃ可愛い！これはね、まあ、今日たくさんいろんなみこが出てきましたきっと！
It's super cute! I'm sure lots of different Mikos appeared today!
どーも！可愛い！
Hello! So cute!
おるだん先生いつもありがとう！
Orudan-sensei, thank you as always!
そして、続いては、
And next up,
じゃーん！
ta-da!
こっちな！今回の目玉、35Pコピーのエリートパーカーとなっております。
is this one! Our main highlight, the Elite Hoodie for all 35P.
こちらもですね、ま、後々分かるんだけど、
This one also, well, you'll see later on,
ま、この特別仕様となっているんですね。何が特別とは言いませんけど。
well, it's a special edition. I won't say what makes it special, though.
めっちゃおしゃれでしょ？可愛いでしょう？
Super stylish, right? Isn't it cute?
みんな買ってね、これ可愛い。本当しっかりしています。
Everyone buy it, it's so cute. It's really well-made.
はい！
Yes!
続いて、
Next up,
はい！
yes!
こちらはみこ＆みこにゃにえのダイカットクッション！
is the Miko & Mikodanye die-cut cushion!
なんかあの、表が、あのさっきのパーカーを着てるみこになってまして、裏がみこにゃにえがいるというね。
The front features Miko wearing the hoodie from earlier, and the back features Mikodanye.
で、側面のデザインも可愛い！
And the side design is also cute!
なもり先生ありがとうございます！可愛い！
Namori-sensei, thank you! So cute!
続いて、じゃーん！
Next, ta-da!
はい、こちらは、えみコピーの皆さんがね、欲しいであろう、みコピー安全証明書となっておりまーす、じゃーん！
And this is the Mikopii Safety Certificate that all you Mikopii probably want, ta-da!
こちらはまあ、ね、安全を保証されたみコピーが結構いるらしいので、みこが発行してあげました。
Since apparently quite a few Mikopii want their safety guaranteed, Miko issued these for you.
感謝ししろこれはね、もうみんなぜひね、チェックしてください。
Be grateful for this, everyone definitely check it out.
この小さい黒文字は、見ないでね！
Don't look at the tiny black text!
はい、ということで、こちらがね、あのフルセットとなっております。
And with that, this is the full set.
そして、購入特典には、なんと！ボボボボン！
And for the purchase bonus, what do you know! Boom!
え、ポストカードがついてきます。
Um, a postcard is included.
こちらは、箱押し複製サイン＆メッセージ入りのポストカードです。
This postcard features a foil-stamped replica signature and message.
あのたくさんね、いっぱい書いたので、皆さんぜひゲットしてね、よろしくな！
I wrote a whole bunch, so everyone be sure to get one, okay!
わー！
Yay!
はーい、ということで、急ぎ、急ぎ気味なんだよ。
Hah... Alright, so, I'm kind of in a rush.
ああ、
Ah,
疲れた。
I'm tired.
お？
Hm?
あれ？
Huh?
お前なんかなんかチョコチョコ現れやがって！
Hey, why are you suddenly scurrying in here?!
なんだよ、ちょっと、しかもなんかちょっとちっちゃくね？ちっちゃいんだよな。
What is this, plus you're kinda small? You're tiny.
あ、なになに？
Ah, what is it?
え、告知？あ、告知を、あ、告知を持ってきてくれたの？
Eh, an announcement? Ah, did you bring an announcement?
しかもなんか手作りになってるんだけど。はい！
Plus it's handmade. Here!
それでは、じゃあ告知なになに？こちら、どうろ…え？何これ？
Well then, let's see what the announcement is. This is a road... Eh? What's this?
え、これ、なになに？え、何これ？
Eh, what is this? Eh, what is this?
え、なんか野良から手紙来てなんですけど！
Eh, wait, I got a letter from a stray!
え、ちょっと待って、待って待って。これ大して長くないし、いいの？これ結構押してるんですけどのに。
Eh, wait a second, wait, wait. This isn't that long, is it okay? Even though we're running way over time.
えーっと、
Um...
さくらみこさん、4周年おめでとうございます。
"Sakura Miko-san, congratulations on your 4th anniversary."
Vtuberとして活躍できる方を探していた中で、みこさんを見つけて声をかけさせてもらいました。
"While looking for someone who could succeed as a VTuber, I found Miko-san and reached out to you."
そうだね、みこスカウトしたね。
That's right, Miko scouted you.
え、最初はみんなで動画制作を頑張っていましたが、なかなか大変でしたね。
"At first, everyone worked hard on video production, but it was quite tough."
新しい取り組みもしようとしておばけ屋敷企画をしたり。
"Trying new things like doing a haunted house project."
そのあとライブ配信中の中心の活動に切り替えて、このライブのメンバーも快く受け入れてくれたことで、ようやくおばあちゃんの強みやポテンシャルを生かして成長できたことに、
"After that, shifting our focus to live streaming, and having the live members warmly accept us, allowed us to finally grow by utilizing our strengths and potential,"
当時はぐっと胸を熱くしていました。
"which really warmed my heart at the time."
え、いろんな行き違いから大変な時期もありましたが、打ち合わせでみんなで泣いて頑張っていこうと決めた日のことも今でも覚えてます。
"There were tough times due to various misunderstandings, but I still remember the day we cried together in a meeting and decided to do our best."
苦しいときに良い感謝として支えてくれたこともとても感謝しています。
"I'm also very grateful for how you supported me with sincere gratitude during tough times."
今では持ち前のサービス精神と企画力を生かして、ソロライブ運動会やプロファイターなどたくさんの視聴者を楽しませたり感動させられる配信を実現していってることに非常に頼もしく思っています。
"Now, utilizing your innate service spirit and planning skills, I find it incredibly reliable that you're making broadcasts that entertain and move many viewers through solo live streams, sports festivals, and pro-fighting."
思っていますし、一視聴者としても楽しませてもらってます。みなみこさんの頑張りはもちろん、世の中にそのとき何が求められているかに合わせて柔軟に行動を変えていけたのが良かったと振り返れば思います。
"I think so, and I enjoy it as a viewer too. Looking back, I think it was great that Miko-san's hard work, of course, was matched by the ability to flexibly adapt your actions to what was needed in the world at that time."
え、新しいことに挑戦することは大変ですが、挑戦しないと始まらないですし、これからも世界中のより多くの人たちを楽しませられるタレントを目指して、いろんなことに挑戦していってもらえればと思います。一緒に頑張っていきましょう！よろしくお願いします！
"Taking on new things is tough, but nothing starts without trying, and I hope you'll continue to take on various challenges aiming to be a talent who can entertain even more people around the world. Let's do our best together! Best regards!"
2022年8月1日タニャゴォ。
"August 1, 2022. Tanyagoo."
え、何？こんなの渡すの？タニャゴォ？
Eh, what? You're giving me something like this? Tanyagoo?
いや、ちょっとありがとうございます！いや、なんかね、
No, thank you so much! No, you know...
ないんですかって言われたんだよね。
People were asking me, "Aren't you doing it?"
いや、こんなこと、あの、本当に初めてもらったんですけど
Well, something like this, um, I've actually received for the first time, but
いや、なんか、4周年だからね、
well, you know, it's my 4th anniversary, so
なんか本当に、あ、いろんなことがあったなと今ね、すごいね、あの、たくさん振り返ってました。
um, really, oh, I feel like so many things happened, and right now, you know, I've been reflecting on so much.
ありがとう、やこ！やこをね、あの、誘っていただいて
Thank you, Yako! Inviting me, Yako, um,
そして途中にね、ホロライブに参加させていただいて、あの、みんなにね、本当に支えられております。
and letting me join Hololive along the way, um, I've really been supported by everyone.
みなさん、スタッフさんもどうもありがとう。
Everyone, thank you so much, staff too.
いやいや！やこちゃんに違うでしょ！もっと大事な、もっと大事なじゃないけど、ありますよね？
No, no! That's not it, Yako-chan! More important... well, not more important, but there is something, right?
はい。
Yes.
それでは、告知！ド――ン！
And now, the announcement! Ta-da!
さくらみこ 1st Album 制作決定！目標の1つですね！やったー！
Sakura Miko's 1st Album production decided! It's one of my goals! Yay!
そして、第一弾は、なんと、あの！もう、神、神、神作編曲家、DECO*27さんが作曲してくださいました！それがこちら！
And the first installment is, amazingly, um! The god, god, god composer and arranger, DECO*27-san composed it for us! Here it is!
ベイビーダンス！こちらはですね、え、このあとちょっと時間が遅くなっちゃったので、22時、え、途中20分？20分からのプレミア公開となっておりますが、皆さん絶対見てね！そして、24時にはですね、え、各所音楽サービス、各所音楽サービスで、あの配信があります！
"Baby Dance"! As for this, um, since it got a bit late after this, it'll be a premiere starting from 22:00, um, midway 20 minutes? 20 minutes, but everyone, definitely watch it! And at 24:00, um, on various music services, on various music services, there will be a release!
ふうー！ということで、まあ、みこはいろいろダメダメなところもありますし、いろいろ頑張ってやってきたけど、まあね、夢が1つかないますということで、制作頑張っていこう！
Whew! So, well, Miko has all sorts of clumsy parts too, and I've tried my best at various things, but you know, since one of my dreams is coming true, let's do our best with production!
それじゃあ、そんな気になる、ベイビーダンス！みんな聴きたいよね？じゃあ、新しい髪型も、そう、気になっちゃうね？それじゃあ、行ってくるよ！ありがとう！もう！
Well then, that song you're curious about, "Baby Dance"! Everyone wants to listen, right? Well, the new hairstyle too, that's right, you're curious about it, right? Well then, I'm going! Thank you! Jeez!
うー、あー、もー、はい
Ooh, ah, mo, ready!
やだやだ ミスってらんない、ね？
No way, no way, I can't afford to make mistakes, okay?
ベイビーダンス
Baby Dance
真っ赤なハート差し出して…
Extending a bright red heart...
そんなのやっぱ妄想じゃん
That's just imagination after all.
そっちはどう思ってるの
What do you think on your end?
言いかけて仕舞う 無理みたい
Trying to speak up and holding back, seems impossible.
こんなんじゃってわかっているんだ もっとハメにハマっていくんだ
I know it's like this, yet I fall deeper into it.
頑張りたい あたしに期待 ぎゅーだってしたいかも…かもん
Wanting to try hard, expecting of myself, maybe I want a hug too... c'mon.
ちょっとは変われていますか？
Have I changed even a little bit?
足りないとかばっかだけど
It's all about what's lacking, but
ポンでコツでドジじゃないあたしだったら きみはだめだよね？
if I were someone who isn't clumsy and goof-prone, you wouldn't want me, right?
ねえもうやだやだ ミスってらんない もうやだやだ 踊ってベイビーダンス
Hey, no more, no way, I can't mess up, no more, no way, dance, Baby Dance!
あたしはまだ諦めない
I still haven't given up.
でもでも 全然だめかも
But, but, maybe it's totally hopeless.
だってベイビーダンス うまくできないの
Because, Baby Dance, I can't do it well.
だってベイビーダンス 伝えられないの
Because, Baby Dance, I can't convey it.
もっと可愛くなりたいのに どうしたらいいとかわかんないし
Even though I want to become cuter, I don't know what I should do.
やだやだ ミスってらんない、ね？
No way, no way, I can't afford to make mistakes, okay?
あーやっちまった こんなはずじゃ
Ah, I messed up, this wasn't how it should be.
どうしてどうして わかっているのに
Why, why, even though I understand,
見せたくないとか透けちゃって 無理無理
things I don't want to show bleed through, no way, no way.
でも 期待はしたいな いいですか？
But I want to have expectations, is that okay?
ポンもコツもドジも全部あたしなんだよ ちゃんと見ていてほしい
Clumsiness, awkwardness, and blunders are all a part of me, I want you to watch properly.
ねえもうやだやだ ぐずって後悔 もうやだやだ 回ってベイビーダンス
Hey, no more, no way, whining and regretting, no more, no way, spin, Baby Dance!
だめなあたし塗り替えたい
I want to repaint this useless me.
でもでも 全然だめかも
But, but, maybe it's totally hopeless.
だってベイビーダンス うまくできないの
Because, Baby Dance, I can't do it well.
だってベイビーダンス 伝えられないの
Because, Baby Dance, I can't convey it.
もっと可愛くなりたいのに どうしたらいいとかわかんないし
Even though I want to become cuter, I don't know what I should do.
まだまだいけるかな まだまだ言えるかな まだまだできるかな まだまだ…うう…
Can I still go on? Can I still say it? Can I still do it? Still... ugh...
ポンでコツでドジでだめで足りないとかばっかだって きっとやめないんだ
Even if I'm clumsy, awkward, blunder-prone, useless, and lacking, I'll definitely never stop.
ポンでコツでドジでだめで足りないとかばっかだって 見ていてほしい
Even if I'm clumsy, awkward, blunder-prone, useless, and lacking, I want you to watch me.
ねえもうやだやだ ミスってらんない もうやだやだ 踊ってベイビーダンス あたしはまだ諦めない
Hey, no more, no way, I can't mess up, no more, no way, dance, Baby Dance, I still haven't given up!
ほらほら 全然だめじゃない
Look, look, it's not totally hopeless at all!
だってベイビーダンス うまくできるから
Because, Baby Dance, I can do it well.
だってベイビーダンス 伝えられるから もっと可愛くなりたいから
Because, Baby Dance, I can convey it, because I want to become cuter.
どんな時だってそう 頑張れるし だってベイビーダンス
No matter when, I can try my best, because it's Baby Dance!
だってベビダンス 君に届くまで
'Cause it's a baby dance, until it reaches you,
だってベビダンス 君に会えるまで
'Cause it's a baby dance, until I can meet you,
もっと可愛くなりたいから
Because I want to become even cuter,
どんな時だってそう 頑張れるし
No matter what, I can always do my best,
やだやだ ミスってらんない、ね？
No way, no way, I can't afford to mess up, right?
想像なんてしてなかった現況
A reality I never could have imagined,
君もそう思った?
Did you think so too?
“最高”で止まらないように更新したい
I want to update it so it doesn't stop at "the best".
叶えたい夢まであとどれくらい?
How much longer until the dream I want to fulfill?
誰も行ったことがない場所へ
To a place no one has ever been,
たどり着くまでは僕ら止まれない
Until we reach it, we can't stop.
僕だけじゃ作れないモノ
Things that cannot be made by me alone,
僕とか君とかあしたとか
Like me, you, and tomorrow,
恋とか愛とかまとめて全部
Romance, love, putting it all together.
君を置いてどっかに行っちゃうとか
Leaving you behind and going somewhere else,
君がくれた音に 弾けた火花に
To the sound you gave me, to the bursting sparks,
初めましてから ずっと恋しちゃってるんだよ
Ever since we first met, I've been falling in love.
君のいない未来 考えらんないよ
I can't imagine a future without you.
これからも二人のがいいじゃん
We're better off together from now on, right?
一途になるほど逃げたくなってきたよ
The more devoted I become, the more I wanted to run away.
散々な僕のこと 呼んでくれてありがとう
Thank you for calling out to such a hopeless me.
君のいない未来 考えらんないよ
I can't imagine a future without you.
これからも二人で
Together from now on as well.
妄想 膨らんでくストーリー
Delusions expanding into a story,
感傷 やけに凹んじゃって
Sentiments getting overly depressed,
代償 求めすぎはやーょ
Demanding too much compensation is a no-no.
終わらない愛の連盟
A federation of never-ending love.
驚かしたいから内緒なんだ
It's a secret because I want to surprise you.
君の愛がいつも勝っちゃうこと
The fact that your love always wins out
許さないよ 君以外はヤダ
I won't forgive it! Anyone other than you is a no.
我儘はタダ
Selfishness is free.
変わらないトキメキを
An unchanging heartbeat
絶叫しちゃうのはバカ
Screaming it out is foolish.
君がくれた音に 弾けた火花に
To the sound you gave me, to the bursting sparks,
初めましてから ずっと恋しちゃってるんだよ
Ever since we first met, I've been falling in love.
君のいない未来 考えらんないよ
I can't imagine a future without you.
これからも二人のがいいじゃん
We're better off together from now on, right?
一途になるほど逃げたくなってきたよ
The more devoted I become, the more I wanted to run away.
散々な僕のこと 呼んでくれてありがとう
Thank you for calling out to such a hopeless me.
君のいない未来 考えらんないよ
I can't imagine a future without you.
これからも二人で
Together from now on as well.
それがいいじゃん
That's even better, right?
乙女解剖で遊ぼうよ
Let's play with maiden dissection.
ドキドキしたいじゃん誰だって
Everyone wants to make their heart pound, right?
アンドロイドガールおかしくなっちゃった
The android girl has gone a bit crazy.
痛みのないキスが離せない
Can't let go of painless kisses.
僕らヴァンパイア
We are vampires.
いいよ吸っちゃっていいよ
It's alright, go ahead and bite.
もう無理もう無理だって悪い子じゃない
"I can't take it anymore," I'm not a bad kid.
こんな歌歌ったんだって
Just singing a song like this,
君が輝けるように
So that you can shine brightly.
想像なんてしてなかった現況
A reality I never could have imagined,
君もそう思った?
Did you think so too?
“最高”で止まらないように更新したい
I want to update it so it doesn't stop at "the best".
叶えたい夢まであとどれくらい?
How much longer until the dream I want to fulfill?
誰も行ったことがない場所へ
To a place no one has ever been,
たどり着くまでは僕ら止まれない
Until we reach it, we can't stop.
僕だけじゃ作れないモノ
Things that cannot be made by me alone,
僕とか君とかあしたとか
Like me, you, and tomorrow,
恋とか愛とかまとめて全部
Romance, love, putting it all together.
君を置いてどっかに行っちゃうとか
Leaving you behind and going somewhere else,
君がくれた音に 弾けた火花に
To the sound you gave me, to the bursting sparks,
初めましてから ずっと恋しちゃってるんだよ
Ever since we first met, I've been falling in love.
君のいない未来 考えらんないよ
I can't imagine a future without you.
これからも二人のがいいじゃん
We're better off together from now on, right?
一途になるほど逃げたくなってきたよ
The more devoted I become, the more I wanted to run away.
散々な僕のこと 呼んでくれてありがとう
Thank you for calling out to such a hopeless me.
君のいない未来 考えらんないよ
I can't imagine a future without you.
これからも二人で
Together from now on as well.
それがいいじゃん
That's even better, right?
乙女解剖で遊ぼうよ
Let's play with maiden dissection.
ドキドキしたいじゃん誰だって
Everyone wants to make their heart pound, right?
アンドロイドガールおかしくなっちゃった
The android girl has gone a bit crazy.
痛みのないキスが離せない
Can't let go of painless kisses.
僕らヴァンパイア
We are vampires.
いいよ吸っちゃっていいよ
It's alright, go ahead and bite.
もう無理もう無理だって悪い子じゃない
"I can't take it anymore," I'm not a bad kid.
こんな歌歌ったんだって
Just singing a song like this,
君が輝けるように
So that you can shine brightly.
はい、ということで4周年来てくれてみんなありがとね！
So, thank you all so much for coming to my 4th anniversary!
このあとベビダンスは22時20分にプレミア公開！
After this, "Baby Dance" will premiere at 10:20 PM!
そして22時30分からはメンゲンもあります、見に来てね！
And starting at 10:30 PM, there's also a members-only stream, come check it out!
みんな本当に本当にいつもありがと！大好きだよ！
Thank you all so, so much as always! I love you!